Alexandre Gbaguidi Aïsse | CV

22 Rue de la République, 92150 Suresnes, France

□ +33 642426980 • ☑ a.gbaguidiaisse@gmail.com • **in** agbaguidiaisse ☐ shumpaga

Looking for a Computer Thesis Subject

Profile

I have been introduced to academic research during my **Research** specialization at EPITA. It played a key role in my work at Bentley Systems leading me to submit **two patents** [2, 1]. After two years as a Software Engineer, I understood that I have a strong passion for research and I want to do a PhD. I have had some experiences in: **3D Reconstruction, Point Clouds, Graph Theory, Finite-State Machine, Data, Cloud Computing**.

Experiences

Bentley Systems - Reality Modeling Team

Paris, France

Software Engineer 3D Reconstruction, Point Clouds, Geometry, Graph Theory Sep 2018 - to date End-of-studies internship Optimization, C++, Python, R, SQL, ReactFeb 2018 - Aug 2018

Improving ContextCapture¹ software and its cloud service :

- Better point cloud support [3] with :
 - · An algorithm that determines one or more scanner positions in a point cloud [2],
 - · An algorithm that estimates which scanner created each point [1].
- Complete rewrite of the Job/Task graph mechanism, performance measures.
- Abstract and converge Cloud/Desktop architectures.

LRDE (Research and Development Laboratory of EPITA)

Paris, France

Student Researcher Finite-State Machine, Graph Theory, Model Checking

Sep 2016 - Jan 2018

- Various contributions to Spot²:
 - · Improve a SAT-based (Boolean satisfiability) graph minimization algorithm using an incremental approach [5]
 - · Add co-Büchi automata support and conversions from other common classes to co-Büchi [4]
 - · Add Persistence/Recurrence membership testing of LTL⁴ formulæ using co-Büchi automata
- Turorials : help students to quickly master programming notions being seen in lectures.

Education

EPITA – Computer Science Research Specialization

• Graduate school of Engineering and Computer Science

Sep 2013 – Sep 2018

Paris, France

Staffordshire University – Semester Abroad

Stafford, England

Real-time and embedded systems

Jan 2015 - Mai 2015

Skills

Languages: French (Native), Russian (Native), English (TOEIC 850)

Programming: C, C++, C#, Python, R, Javascript, React, NodeJS, Scala, Java, PostgreSQL, SQLite.

OS: Linux / UNIX, Mac Os X, Windows.

Interests: Education, Audio recording, mix, master, computer-aided music, travels, event planning.

¹ContextCapture is a 3D Reconstruction Software which turns point clouds and/or images into realistic 3D Models.

²Spot is a C++14 library for LTL, ω -automata³ manipulation and model checking: spot.lrde.epita.fr.

³A variation of finite-state automata which runs on infinite, rather than finite, strings as input.

⁴Linear Temporal Logic : used to express time-aware conditions. Used in model checking.

Submitted Patents

- [1] Gbaguidi Aïsse Alexandre Novel Cyril. "Assigning each point of a point cloud to a scanner position of a plurality of different scanner positions in a point cloud". Unpublished yet.
- [2] Gbaguidi Aïsse Alexandre Novel Cyril. "Determining One Or More Scanner Positions In A Point Cloud". 20200371214A1. Nov. 2020. URL: https://patents.google.com/patent/US20200371214A1/.

Internship Reports

- [3] Gbaguidi Aïsse Alexandre. Improving Point Cloud Support of ContextCapture: ScanFinder, Point Cloud Visibility and Point Cloud Compression. Tech. rep. End-Of-Engineering-Cycle Internship Report. Kremlin-Bicêtre, France: Bentley Systems, Aug. 2018. URL: https://github.com/shumpaga/end-of-studies-internship-report/blob/master/internship-report-alexandregbaguidiaisse.pdf.
- [4] Gbaguidi Aïsse Alexandre. *A co-Büching Toolbox*. Tech. rep. 1705. EPITA Research and Development Laboratory (LRDE), 2017. URL: https://github.com/shumpaga/techreports/blob/master/A% 20co-B%C3%BCching%20Toolbox.pdf.
- [5] Gbaguidi Aïsse Alexandre. Implementation of ω-automata Minimization Techniques in Spot, a Model Checking Library. Tech. rep. 3rd Year Internship Report. Kremlin-Bicêtre, France: LRDE, Jan. 2017. URL: https://github.com/shumpaga/spot-internship-report/blob/master/report.pdf.